[car engine starts, revving]
[tires screeching]
[upbeat instrumental music plays]
[Jerry] All right, let’s get real.
This is a 1964 Volvo 122 sedan,
in pearl white
with a red leatherette interior,
and red wheels with hubcaps
that have red insignias.
In Europe, these cars were known
as Amazons.
[car engine revs]
It’s got a four cylinder engine
and a four-speed gear box.
It has 90 horsepower.
That’s enough.
This was also the very first
production car to come with seat belts
and a padded safety dashboard.
Cars are always the most vivid expression
of what a culture is about
in the time that it was made.
This car is the essence
of great '60s Swedish values.
Honest, hardworking, unfussy,
not out to impress,
and built to last.
It also happens to be the personal taste
of my unbelievably talented
and funny extra special guest today,
Ms. Kristen Wiig.
Kristen is of Norwegian descent and loves
old Volvos.
I think there’s a connection there.
I know Sweden and Norway are
two different countries,
but come on, are they really?
It’s also a perfect car for the kind of
hipster neighborhood that she lives in.
Hipsters seem to like things
that are old and out of it
to show how young and into it they are.
Like bicycles with only one gear.
How dumb.
But the bottom of my jeans are rolled up,
my sunglasses have translucent frames,
I’m ready to have a hipster day.
[telephone ringing]
[Kristen] Hello?
Kristen, it’s Jerry Seinfeld.
[Kristen] Oh, my gosh, hi.
[Jerry] What kind of morning have you had?
[Kristen] A great morning.
I actually drink this stuff called
mushroom coffee.
[Jerry] Well, I know a place that makes
moss and wood bark omelets.
[Kristen chuckles]
I’m Jerry Seinfeld, and this is
Comedians in Cars Getting Coffee.
Oh, my gosh.
[jazz music playing]
-Are you kidding?
-You know what this is?
[Kristen] It’s an Amazon. [laughs]
-Oh, my God, Jerry, this is insane.
-You’re going to lose your mind.
-I already have.
-You’re going, yeah.
[Jerry] When you open the door,
tell me how that feels.
Oh, yeah. It’s a solid click.
[Kristen exhales]
[giggles]
Oh, thank you.
-A stranger just handed me my...
-Oh, good, are you doing a western later?
[both laughing]
[jazz music playing]
-[Kristen] Oh, my gosh, it’s a tank.
-[Jerry] It's a tank.
[Kristen]
My boyfriend is very into Volvos.
He is so excited about the Volvos.
-And actually we, um...
-How did that happen?
How did that come up?
Well, his parents have,
I think they have three,
and he drove one in high school,
had kind of mentioned that
he drove Volvos, like old Volvos
and I was like, "I love old Volvos."
How long did you know your boyfriend
before this information came out?
-Were you sleeping together?
-He did love that I liked them so much.
I mean, it definitely was a bonding thing.
[Jerry] I love two people
getting heated up
and jumping into bed
because of an old Volvo.
-That is hilarious.
-I know, right? It’s kind of rare.
[slow jazz playing]
Isn’t this nice and relaxing?
[Kristen] Yeah.
So relaxing.
-Come on-- Yeah, the breeze.
-The breeze is nice.
The Volvo-ness.
Oh, my God, I saw the camera over there,
I was like, "They’re filming us."
-I didn’t quite--
-I’ve had that same reaction.
-"Leave us alone!"
-I thought, "Oh, my..."
"We’re just people."
[jazz music playing]
[inaudible]
-[Jerry] What do you do for fun?
-[Kristen] I play the ukulele.
And I’m working on
a ukulele album right now.
Waterskiing, things like that.
You waterskiing is a really funny image.
I just slalomed for the first time.
It’s a good workout.
Oh, it’s idiotic.
[upbeat jazz music playing]
[inaudible]
-Oh, this is a great bookstore.
-Let’s go in for the smell.
[sniffing]
Oh, yeah.
-[Jerry] So you like LA?
-[Kristen] I do.
-[Jerry] How come?
-I think when I moved here,
when I was in the Groundlings,
it was just such a great time for me.
I originally came out here ‘cause
I wanted to act and stuff.
But I got here and I was like,
"What do I do? I have no experience."
-So I didn’t do anything.
-Right.
I went and saw the show
and I’d never seen improv in my life.
-I didn’t know what it was.
-Right.
So getting suggestions,
I'm like, "What’s going on?
What are they gonna say?"
It was so funny and I was like,
"I want to do that."
-Right.
-Like I feel like my brain is better
at something like that,
than reading a script and then doing it
and then people can be like,
"Is that good?"
-I still do shows there once in a while.
-You’re kidding. Oh, my God.
And sometimes you’re on the floor,
you’re sitting there, just like my home.
[inaudible]
-Oh, look at that. That looks great.
-Oh, my God. That looks amazing,
-those fries?
-Oh, good for you.
Look at that, he ordered--
he ordered a dog.
Don’t eat it.
[dramatic instrumental music playing]
You know what? I’ve never been
inside House of Pies.
We’re going to House of Pies.
Oh, this is amazing.
[dramatic music continues]
[Kristen gasps]
Smells like crust.
[jazz music playing]
The greatest bit I’ve ever seen
on an awards show,
is when you and Will
did the Golden Globes,
‘cause everyone was laughing before
you started.
You walked out there with this look
of wonder, at the Golden Globes.
The whoriest night of the year
in Hollywood.
A town of whores.
[audience laughing]
We hadn’t seen the movies.
-Mariole, Mariole Streep.
-Mariole Streep. Mariole Streep.
-Hope Springs and she’s the sassy sheriff.
-Hope Springs, my gosh and she plays...
The only thing we knew we were going
to say is that "get out" part.
-She says, "You, you get out of here."
-"You, you, you get out of here."
-[audience laughing]
-[chuckling]
There’s the guy who ate the dog.
-He didn’t eat the dog.
-Well, we can’t see his legs.
That dog does look edible, by the way.
-He’s like already charbroiled.
-Yeah.
[both laughing]
[jazz music playing]
[bell dings]
I mean, I didn’t get SNL until I was 30.
-Really?
-Yeah.
I actually waited tables
at Universal Studios,
in the executive dining room.
So I see people now and I’m like,
"I used to give you Arnold Palmers."
I worked in a flower shop
for like three years.
It’s like a floral design studio,
is what they call it.
[smacks lips, laughs]
That’s a character.
Someone that works as a florist,
and is constantly making the "pop" sound.
Oh, these are the times I wish
I was still on the show.
That’s what you’re great at.
You see somebody twirling their hair and
you just fill in the rest of the picture.
I take like little things people like
say or do, and you’re like,
"What if I just took that,
and then like, exploded it."
Like, I did this character on SNL,
Aunt Linda,
I don’t know if you ever saw it.
She’s a movie critic. It started because
I was on a plane,
and they were showingThe Matrix
and this woman was so confused by
the movie.
And so loud about it because she had
her headphones on, and she’s like,
"What? Now where are they?"
And she was doing it so loud
and I just took my head--
and I was writing down things
she was saying.
-She’s like, "Now they’re flying? What?"
-That is so...
What was the first thing you did
that you felt,
"I think this works?"
I like doing the Target lady.
I think I did it in my audition.
We have one candle
that’s got like a pine scent on the top,
and on the bottom it’s like a nutmeg.
So the top when you burn that down,
it’s a whole other candle.
You know, that show it’s like you
don’t hear for a while, it’s very like,
ambiguous.
I did my audition and then...
-I met with Lorne, and everyone’s like...
-Right.
"Oh, well, you met with Lorne,
that’s like, you’ve got the job."
And I was like,
"Oh, my gosh, this is amazing."
Like, I never heard anything and like
the summer and then the season started.
And I was like, "Well I’m not there."
-And what were you doing?
-I was living here.
And then it was like, four shows in,
and they called me
and they were like,
"Can you come next week?"
I don’t think they told anyone
I was joining the cast.
I came in and I was like, "Hi."
Just so awkward.
I remember like when I first started,
I was like, "Oh, the moment
I feel comfortable here,
is when I have to leave."
I remember year four, I was like,
"I’m done.
I can’t do anything else with my voice."
Like I don’t, I really felt that way,
"I have no more, I’ve done every accent,
I don’t have any more characters in me,
like what?"
That’s so funny.
[jazz music playing]
I don’t like being in front of people.
Being in a character, I could get on stage
and talk for half an hour.
-Yeah.
-Like, my biggest fear is like,
being at a big dinner party and someone
be like, "Kristen, tell that story about,"
and then I just immediately go into
the sweats.
-Do you have any--
-I’m like, "Everyone’s looking at me.
-What’s my mouth doing?"
-Yeah.
Like that’s what I’m thinking in my head.
It’s weird to describe myself as
like being funny. I don’t know why.
-I know I have, it’s a weird... I...
-I think we can get past that.
-I don’t know.
-When you go out to dinner
with people that aren’t funny,
do you have trouble focusing?
Someone will tell a story and then,
"Yeah, and then we just you know,
we all left."
And it’s silent, and like everyone’s fine,
but if that were me,
-I would have a panic attack.
-Yes.
And I always wonder, do they
know they just went in the toilet?
-No.
-They do think everyone’s going to go,
-"Oh, my God."
-"That happened?"
-"Really? You just bumped into them."
-"And you knew them from before."
[Jerry laughing]
[jazz music playing]
I get doughnuts sometimes for my birthday
instead of cake.
That’s a great idea.
And I had my birthday
when we were shooting Ghostbusters,
and they got a huge doughnut, it was like,
that big, with candles in it.
It was delicious.
Really? I’m surprised.
I know, but it was.
It was like a big doughnut.
Like, how are they gonna
have the consistency?
-This is not gonna be good. It was.
-Not gonna be good.
You don’t have doughnuts, do you?
No doughnuts. We have a lot of pie.
-Peach pie is in season.
-[Jerry] What are you feeling?
Peach pie in season. I just heard that.
-Do you want the peach pie?
-Yes.
Let's do that.
[jazz music playing]
We’re trying to figure out,
where’s the point?
-[Kristen] Oh, I see, look. That’s it.
-[Jerry] Oh.
-[Kristen] See the lift?
-[Jerry] I recognize it.
-[Jerry] There’s the back border.
-Back border. As the chefs call it.
How did you feel at that last SNL,
that fantastic thing they did for you?
I waited months before I watched it.
-Really?
-And I like lost it, oh, yeah.
It was the hardest thing I had to do,
even though it was my decision to do it.
Was there any discussion of you not going?
No. It didn’t feel right to stay.
I missed my family.
I needed to see daylight.
-And like go to the dentist.
-It’s true.
‘Cause you write all Tuesday night,
and then come home
and you’d be in the car,
and people are running, up early.
And I’m like, "What’s that like?"
I do miss the quick puzzle pieces,
you know,
like someone walks up to you, like,
"We have to cut 20 seconds out of that."
-It’s fun, right?
-Yeah, it's so fun.
-It’s like you’re a bomb squad.
-I know, you do.
-Because your brain is working so fast...
-Yes.
...to figure out a math problem
that has nothing to do with anything.
-But then you figure it out.
-Yeah.
And it’s one in the morning.
Then it’s over and like,
"Oh, my God. How did we do that?"
And it ended on time, and like,
"Okay, see you tomorrow."
[Jerry] I don’t want to see anything
on anybody’s phone anymore.
This thing has become...
Just anyone’s hand reaching towards me
with a phone in it.
I don’t care if you saw an alien changing
a tire on his saucer.
I don’t care what you got.
-I don’t care what it is.
-I don’t think they’ll have tires.
That’s the whole point, they hover--
-Well, that’s the joke.
-That is the joke.
-The part I thought was funny.
-Yeah.
Orthodontic care for children is
so down now.
-When you were a kid...
-Yes--
It was one chair, right?
You go in there now, it’s like 20 chairs.
They know exactly when to put them on.
They start with the palate expander,
then the retainer.
-Palate expander?
-Yeah.
I wanted palate expanders
to be a Spider-Man villain.
[both laughing]
He goes like this, and people are like...
[jazz music playing]
[Jerry] There was a guy that used to have
a bullhorn on stage.
His name was Glenn Super.
He had the bullhorn,
"This comes in handy a lot of times
in real life."
And he would go,
"Some coffee would be nice."
[chuckles]
The whole setup of the thing,
the bullhorn, the restaurant,
the person wants coffee,
that’s not the funny part.
The funny part is he didn’t
even ask for it.
Yes.
-It’s just a comment.
-Yeah.
If you would’ve said it another way,
or asked...
-"May I have some more coffee?" That's...
-That's not funny.
[jazz music playing]
Did you see that billboard on La Cienega
for sugar models?
-No.
-It said, "Sugar models,
sugar dates, arrangements, social club."
Maybe it’s a modeling agency,
maybe it’s a dessert.
-Yeah.
-Maybe it's both.
Maybe it’s models of things made of sugar?
-It’s just a sweet shop is all.
-That's all.
That’s all it is.
I want three bear claws a week.
Mm-hmm, that’s my arrangement.
And sugar club.
-Social club.
People who just want to sit around
with dessert.
-And talk to people.
-Yeah. About dessert.
Yeah. That sounds like fun.
-Should we call?
-Yeah, call them.
I would like to see you answering
the phone at Sugar Models.
-"Hello."
-[both laughing]
"Sugar Models, connecting beautiful women
with affluent men."
-Yeah. I don’t think this is...
-No, we don’t want to call that.
Nope. We don’t want to do it.
Not from your phone.
"Oh, Jerry Seinfeld’s calling." "Again?"
-Then my wife sees it.
-"Jerry?
Who is Sugar Models?"
[both laughing]
By the way, it was--
$20 dollars is the whole check.
-That’s crazy.
Wait, two servings of eggs, a croissant,
and a piece of pie.
-This place is frozen in time.
-Yeah, the eggs were three dollars.
-Three dollars?
-Yes.
What year is this?
[upbeat music playing]
[inaudible]
[Kristen] Ooh, glasses.
I feel like...
I can make my own salsa.
[Jerry] What do you think of these on me?
You know, I think they actually
fit your head really well.
Salespeople are always dishonest.
You’re being dishonest.
-I’m not being dishonest.
-They don’t look good.
I don’t look good.
Would you suggest I buy these?
I mean, yeah. You look great.
-Horrible. Absolutely horrible.
-They make great gifts.
Just kidding.
[inaudible]
[Jerry] Look at the Jeni’s Ice Cream.
When they get the look of these
stores right...
-Want to go in?
-It drives me nuts.
-At Jeni’s?
-Yeah.
[Jerry laughs]
-[horn honks]
-Excuse me, we have to get to Jeni's.
[both laughing]
[upbeat music playing]
-[Kristen] I’ll do a little heart.
-[woman] Thank you.
Thanks. I wrote "I hate you."
[upbeat music continues]
[Jerry] Know your way home from here?
To my actual house?
Is there another home that
you would live in?
That’s your house,
and you go back to your life now.
Oh. All right.
[Jerry] By the way, House of Pies
sounds dirtier than Sugar Models.
[Kristen laughs]
I’m gonna take one more picture of it.
Oh, it’s so cool. [gasps]
My dogs are here. Hi, guys.
I haven’t seen you in so long. Hello.
[Jerry] This is a nice dog. Oh, my gosh.
-[Kristen] Step-dog.
-[Jerry] Yeah.
[both laughing]